



summary

In my work experience I have been involved in every stage of a product lifecycle: from concept ideation to user research, to IA, to creation of wireframes and prototypes for usability testing, to converting those mock-ups into end-product UIs, then collecting feedback and iterating designs again and again.

I am very result oriented. Rather than counting hours spent on a project, I would target to define and solve the problem, to set a deadline and deliver a measurable result.

Here's what I do:

- ensure that the product is based on data & research;
- organise, structure and label content into a usable and findable shape;
- · observe, ask, learn about users and their needs;
- optimise design to decrease user's confusion and increase confidence;
- synthesise user & product research findings into prototypes to test with users;
- create multi-platform user interfaces that not only look great, but work.

tools

Pen, Paper	Gimp	Proto.io	Catalyst
Whiteboard	Inkscape	Prototyping-On-Paper	Fireworks
Sketch	InDesign	LiveView	Brackets
Photoshop	Balsamiq	Skala Preview	Sublime Text
Illustrator	Axure	Android Design Preview	Komodo Edit

education

2012

BA, Graphic Design

Kingston University, London

2003

BA, Management, Economics & English

National Linguistics University, Kiev

experience

Head of UX at Lifecake. London. 2012-2015

Lifecake is a cross-platform cloud service for parents to store, organise and privately share photos, videos and stories of their children only with the people who care, without spamming the entire world on Facebook.

I have been the first employee at Lifecake. I started with the company as a UX/UI/Web/Graphic designer before the investment rounds. Naturally, I have been involved in all aspects of product and experience design at all stages: from discovery to multiple iterations, including several major redesigns of the web interface and native mobile clients for iPhone, iPad and Android.

This role involved:

- · User & Usability research;
- · Information Architecture;
- · Wireframing, prototyping and user testing;
- · Web analytics;
- UI & Interaction design for Web, phones & tablets; desktop apps (Win, Mac)
- · Content strategy, copyright;
- Brand identity;
- Social media;
- · Print design (photoboks);
- · Video shooting and editing.

UX Consultant at Playenable, London, 2013

Playenable is a service that helps users find and book fitness classes near them and helps sports venues manage their bookings and get exposure to new audience. The company's website and mobile apps have to sell the service, display relevant search results in a user-friendly way, and also enable users to organise and manage schedules, classes and venues via clear dashboards.

My project was to redesign desktop and mobile experiences to better present the idea of the service to customers, facilitate and encourage engagement, increase conversion and retention of the users.

This role involved:

- · UX Strategy;
- · Project management;
- · IA & UX redesign;
- User research, wireframes, prototypes, usability validation;
- · Crossplatform UI.

UX/UI/Graphic Designer at Ambulatoria, Kiev, 2010-2011

Ambulatoria is a medical company based in Kiev, Lviv, Odesa, Dnepropetrovsk and Kharkiv. It specialises in back and neck problems.

I did their first website, branding, corporate identity, print design and advertising materials.

During my work there I used various research techniques, such as: interviews, surveys, open and closed card sorting, task analysis, personas, wireframing and prototyping, usability testing, A/B testing, first click testing, and more. But the most interesting (and the most challenging) part of this project for me was Information Architecture. The website had to contain hundreds of articles, and I had to make sure that all of them are organised in a logical and intuitive way; as well as that the user is able to locate all the relevant information fast and easy. I successfully tested and, after several iterations, implemented a complex navigation system that included 2 equal global menu layers, but still was easy to use.

I wrote all the HTML, CSS and jQuery for the project.

UI/UX Designer, Freelancer, London, 2011-2012

During 2011 - 2012 I worked as a freelancer or volunteer on a number of projects.

Those projects included:

- · User & usability research,
- · Wireframes & prototypes,
- · Mobile UI,
- · Desktop apps,
- · Interaction design,
- · Visual design,

- · Web design and HTML/CSS/jQuery,
- Branding,
- · Logos,
- · Concepts,
- Graphics,
- Design for print.

Stories of selected clients:

Maogma, Frankfurt

Maogma is a luxury travel agent that specialises in Philippines.

I worked with Maogma when they just started off. They had some basic wireframes, a description of the product and the direction. I was involved in designing the website and also I created the logo and branding style for them.

I did competition and task analysis to inform the layout, tweaked site's global navigation according to the results of card-sorting tests, updated the wireframes and converted them into high-fidelity UI at later stages.

I created concepts for the logo and brand according to company's brief, we tested and discussed them, iterated the best ones and tested again to choose the final design. I created a detailed specs document on the branding for the company.

Stories of selected clients (continued):

Sportalise, London

Sportalise is a platform for organising and managing schedules, events and statistics for sport clubs.

The main thing about the work with Sportalise is that I began to love to design dashboards after this. I worked on several projects for this company, including designing brochures. I also designed and wrote the code for the club pages for the website. I did the designs for the 2012 School Games for Sportalise. The work included research and UI design of the homepage, as well as IA and design of the dashboard pages.

Flatclub, London

Flatclub is a marketplace for medium term stays in London and New York.

This is where and when I fell in love with the Redesign: taking what's there, reviewing, analysing and making it look, feel and perform better. I did a series of small to medium tasks for Flatclub, including research and design of various forms, review and redesign of various website sections, graphic design, UI design for specific webpages, user profile pages, flat owner profile pages, review pages, built-in communication module UI.

This project included: Competition Analysis, Wireframes, Prototypes, UI design

London Business School, London

I have done several projects for various LBS events. The most challenging and refreshing one was to brand a yearly Disorientation Week for the class of 2012.

At the beginning of each course, there is a Orientation Week for students at LBS. Which is meant to be an organisational and team building event. And, equally, at the end of each course there is a Disorientation Week for students, which is meant to be fun.

The unofficial theme for the 2012 event was the London Olympics. So the logo and branding had to comprise the topic of the Olympics and a feeling of a total disorientation.

This was a fun and open graphic project. Restriction to use the Olympic symbols if you don't have the official permission only added to the challenge. I prepared myself for the task with visuals research and sketched multiple design concepts, collected feedback on them, picked the best, iterated and tested again, analysed the feedback that I got and converted the sketches into the high-fidelity designs, played some more with colours, backgrounds and text before finalising.

I created 2 versions of the logo (with and without text), an icon and a letterhead style.

The logo was printed on flags, banners and t-shirts for the event and was used online on the website, and on the official materials.

Quality Hotel Hampstead, London

This was a short-term project aimed to improve usability of the website and bring the visuals of the user interface up to date.

Before staring with the homepage layout and visuals, I did some research: task analysis and usability tests of the old site - to better understand the target audience; first click tests, card sorting to better inform content and navigation design; also I did a lot of competition analysis.

Based on the research that I had done, I produced several different wireframes for the homepage, tested the usability's effectiveness and navigation's efficiency, iterated the designs, converted them into several high-fidelity prototypes to test user's satisfaction.

The deliverables of the project were several options of the final designs: tested, thought through and visually updated UI for the company's homepage.